

BALRAM JHA

ADMINISTRATION OPERATIONS HEAD

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A focused professional, military veteran with 26+ years of leadership experiences in all domains of Administration Operations, Property/ Estate matters, Hospitality, Purchase, Store management, Housekeeping, transportation, Catering management, Industrial labourers management, Security, Fire fighting, CCTV and associated services, formulation and implementations of Standard Operating Procedure,

Seeking a senior leadership managerial challenging responsibility to perform & deliver measurable growth to the organization that I am a part of. Also, focused approach in building long term client relations and mentoring team towards success.

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Date of Birth : 08th February, 1968

• Languages: English, Hindi

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Administration Operations, security management, Stores, inventory, material and logistics management
- Logistics procedure training from Indian Air Force
- Project management and real estate management
- Technical and administrative management skill
- Public relations
- Software skills- MS office (Excel, word, PowerPoint presentation)

WORK EXPERIENCE

ASST. GENERAL MANAGER (ADMINISTRATION HOD)

Amrit Cement Pvt. Ltd, Meghalaya | October 2020 - Present

 Looking after and controlling all Administrative activities of the company like, transport management, guest house management, township management, estate management, temple and dispensary/ medical management, asset management. mess upkeep and food arrangements, space management, vendor management, and office managements (Housekeeping, pantry, service, stationary and man power)

SENIOR MANAGER

DB Security Solutions, Gurgaon, Haryana | May 2019 - Sept 2020

- Managing all annual maintenance contract of CCTV, fire fighting system and access control system from clients like JBM, CBRE, CUSHMAN WAKEFIELD, COCA COLA, STRYKER and more.
- Managing team for prompt service with zero tolerance service 24x7
- Assisting management to achieving high volume of business.

HOUSE MANAGER

Chhattisgarh Bhawan (Govt. of Chhattisgarh), New Delhi | June 2016 to April 2019

- Handling hospitality, allotment of accommodations, arrangements of top class amenities, foods and beverages, Administration operations, Estate matters, stores, catering management, housekeeping, transportation, manpower management, their attendance, payment process and establishment with Govt. of Chhattisgarh at Chhattisgarh Bhawan, New Delhi.
- Planning, controlling and supervising security arrangement of establishments, buildings, men, materials and other movable and immovable property against fire, thefts, pilferage, personnel hazards, and unauthorized entry of men and passage of materials.
- Co-ordinating fire-fighting team in case of emergency.
- Initiating E-tendering procedure for all AMC and vendors management
- Liaising with various agencies such as PWD, Fire, Jal Board, Municipal Corporation and all required government department.
- Ensuring proper maintenance of all immovable and movable assets and carry out physical verification of all assets held on the inventory.
- Initiating purchase of items from GeM portal.
- Supervising the work of supervisor, day to day maintenance work from civil and electrical engineering.
- Hospitality of guests like honorable Chief Minister of Chhattisgarh, honorable Governor, Pramukh Lokayukta, Chief Secretary, honorable minister, bureaucrats and their families.

FIELD EXECUTIVE

Davinta Technologies Pvt Ltd | Aug. 2014 to May 2016 a venture of Vattikuti foundation of USA in collaboration with RGVN (Rastriya Gramin Vikas Nidhi) and IDBI bank in Guwahati

- Conducted verification of data in remote area of Assam, authorizing them for issuance of loan with coordination of local NGO RGVN and IDBI bank.
- Conducting field visits to remote areas of Assam as in Project UNNATI
- Co-coordinating with local SHG to assist rural people to get bank loans for their livelihood.

CONTACT INFORMATION

9310746778 balramjha88@gmail.com

Permanent and Correspondence address: H-2/27E&F, 1st floor, Mahavir Enclave, Dwarka sec-1, New Delhi-110045

PERSONALITY TRAITS

- Adaptability to different situations
- Leadership skill & a good team player
- Problem solving ability
- Positive thinking and passionate

SENIOR NON-COMMISSIONED OFFICER

INDIAN AIR FORCE | June 1988 to June 2014

- Trained at Mechanical Training Institute Air Force Station, Tambaram, Chennai
- Worked at Barmer Air Base on various air armament stores, armament administration and material management procedure
- Posted in technical team for production, support for quality check procedure, their maintenance, proper storage, supply and receipt of all explosive from country nodal base as well as from abroad held on the inventory of Indian Air Force
- Worked as key personnel holding the inventory at Pokhran Air Range
- Appointed as an Assistant to CEO at Allahabad (Central Air Command).
 Managed catering facilities of all officers, and staffs.
- Appointed as an Executive Assistant to CEO at Allahabad (Central Air Command).
- Appointed as in charge of Bar and Mess of 300 strength at Kharagpur (Kalaikunda) Air Force Station.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

SIKKIM MANIPAL UNIVERSITY, GANGTOK

MBA in Human Resource

Attended from May 2009- April 2011

Mechanical Training Institute, IAF

Diploma in Mech. Engineering

Attended from June 1988- Dec 1990